The battle that changed the course of history.
Wunderland is a action, war, drama film directed by Steven Luke.
Christmas 1944, The Germans make one final push against
the attacking allied armies in the West.
Robert Cappa and his platoon of 2nd Infantry Division soldiers have been
ordered to hold a vital road junction against the German aggressors.
Cappa and his men must find their faith and strength to stand against their
enemy in the epic fight know as "The Battle of The Bulge."
Sergeant McKeny, played by Jeremy Michael Pereira.
Major McCulley, played by Tom Berenger.
Lieutenant Cappa, played by Steven Luke.
Captain Daniels, played by Aaron Courteau.
Private Rudy, played by Cody Fleury.
'Doc' Anderson, played by Andrew Stecker.
The Miniatur Wunderland (German for: Miniature Wonderland) is, according to
Guinness World Records, the largest model railway system in the world.
It is located at the historic Speicherstadt in Hamburg and is one of
the most popular and most visited sights in Germany.
The exhibition includes around 1,230 digitally
controlled trains with more than 12,000 wagons.
The Wonderland is also designed with around 5,280 houses and bridges, more than 11,800 vehicles – of which
around 350 drive independently on the installation – 52 airplanes and around 290,000 figures.
The system features a recurring day-night lighting cycle
and almost 500,000 built-in LED lights.
Of the 10,000 m2 (107,639 sq ft) of floorspace, the
models occupies 1,694 m2 (18,234 sq ft).
As of May 2025, the railway consisted of 16,491 m (54,104 ft) of track in H0 scale with 3,600 switches and 1,400 signals, divided into twelve sections: Harz mountains, the fictitious
town of Knuffingen, the Alps and Austria, Hamburg, America, Scandinavia, Switzerland, a replica of Hamburg Airport, Italy, Rio de Janeiro, Patagonia and Monaco/Provence.
Planning is also in progress for the construction of sections for
Central America and the Caribbean and perhaps Great Britain.
The film explores themes of world war ii, battle of the bulge,
road battle, german army, american soldiers.
The tone is emotional and intense.